Guide to the David T. Mason Papers 1865-2004
Western Washington University, Center for Pacific Northwest Studies
David T. Mason Papers
1865-2004
1950-2004
Center for Pacific Northwest Studies Goltz-Murray Building 808 25th St Bellingham, WA 98225-9123 Phone: 360 650 7534 Email: cpnws@wwu.edu
XOE_CPNWS0045mason
Mason, David T.
12 linear feet
The collection is comprised of notebooks, journals, photographs, posters, programs, correspondence, reports, speeches and writings, clippings, original scores of music, and publications documenting the academic work, research, and interests of Fairhaven College professor David T. Mason.
David T. Mason was born January 7, 1937 in Berkeley, California. His parents, Lucile (Roush) Mason and Herbert Mason were renowned botanical scientists and longtime faculty at the University of California, Berkeley and Davis. David T. Mason earned his Bachelor of Arts in biology at Reed College in 1958. In 1961, David received a Master of Arts degree in zoology at the University of California, at Davis, where he went on to complete a PhD in Limnology in 1966. Soon after receiving his doctorate, David became an associate professor of Biology at Western Washington University in Bellingham, Washington.
David integrated teaching and research with theatrical productions and creative writing. He was actively involved in producing and directing plays, and creating musical scores for countless Friends of Fairhaven Theater productions. He became especially well known for his performance art piece, “Blue Baroque.”
As a much beloved professor at Fairhaven College, Mason taught a wide variety of inter-disciplinary classes including basic biology and ecology theory and practice. Among the very few publicly ‘out’ gay male teachers in the mid 1960s, David also created one of the first gay and lesbian studies classes in the Pacific Northwest. He was also well known for his theater courses and performances. Of particular note are his "Orpheo," "Dictionary" and "Opera" classes. David emphasized experiential learning. Classes such as the ‘Lynden Recycling Project’ helped increase awareness about the importance of recycling. Students in his gay studies class were invited to learn about gay culture by touring the local gay bar. ‘The Course of the Stream’ encouraged students to study natural habitats along rivers and streams in Whatcom County.
During the late 1960s through 1980s, David pursued various research and activist projects, and was awarded a Fulbright fellowship in 1973, which took him to Uruguay to pursue his environmental research. The Uruguay experience culminated in a series of traveling lectures and multimedia slideshows on environmental concerns which David presented to audiences as varied as learned biology scholars and school children. His sabbaticals and research trips took him mainly to the Alaskan arctic to study the effects of crude oil on natural habitats. His major research interests ranged from limnology studies of Mono Lake in California, and Antarctica, the impacts of sewage treatment and heavy metals on natural bodies of water in the arctic and the Pacific Northwest, and habitat studies along the lower Stehekin River, to ecological effects on plants and animals along the Nooksack River and Lake Abert in Oregon. He also studied the release of chemicals in Bellingham Bay by Georgia-Pacific mill. David produced numerous articles and research papers both published and unpublished for educational presentations and traveling multi-media slideshows.
The David T. Mason Papers reflect the varied interests and research pursuits of this beloved Fairhaven professor and include a small portion of materials relating to the lives of his parents, Lucile (Roush) and Herbert Mason.
Family and Personal papers contains correspondence, photographs and background information about Mason and his immediate family. The Mason and Roush family photographs date from approximately 1865 to the middle of the 1900s and document Herbert Mason’s research expeditions to the arctic during the early 1900s, Yosemite National Park field school, Stanford and Berkeley, California, as well as a host of botanical and geological locations. This series documents his school and formative years, including his experimentation with LSD in the mid 1960s, teaching and scholarly pursuits, and ongoing contact with family, male and female lovers, and friends.
Records pertaining to Mason's education and career comprise the core of his collection, including samples of course materials (lectures and notes) from classes he taught at Western Washington University and at Fairhaven College from the 1970s through the 1990s. Course materials include a clippings file from Mason's Gay Studies class from the early 1970s, as well as handwritten lectures from popular and well-attended biology and ecology classes. Education and Career records also contains project notes, data, published, and unpublished research papers about various sites Mason explored including the Alaskan Arctic, Mono Lake and other sites in California, the Stehekin River in Whatcom County, Washington, and Georgia-Pacific mill among others as well as correspondence and reports from Mason’s sabbaticals and Fulbright travels. The Mason Education records also include slides and field notebooks from Mason's various research projects. Slides include images of people, landmarks, plants, and animals from Bellingham and his world travels. There are also images of theater works and other artistic projects. Locations of slides and field notebooks include: Alaska, Australia, Antarctica, South America, Africa, the Philippines, and Japan.
This collection also contains speeches, lectures, publications and letters of appreciation regarding Mason’s popular and dynamic traveling multi-media slideshows. The collection contains scripts and musical compositions from Friends of Fairhaven Theater productions in which Mason played the vital roles of producer, director, actor and musician. Writings and Art contain samples of Mason's creative writing, drawings, musings, and include several one-of-a-kind local gay publications.
The David T. Mason Papers are organized according to the following series:
Series I. Personal and Family Papers, circa 1865-2004
Series II. Education and Career, circa 1954-2002
Series III. Theatre, circa 1970-1998
Series IV. Writings and Art, circa 1960-1997
The collection is open to the public.
David T. Mason donated his papers to the Center for Pacific Northwest Studies in 2001.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Mason, David T. 1937-
Fairhaven College
Education, Higher --Washington (State) --Bellingham --History --Sources.; Community education--Washington (State)--Bellingham --History--Sources.; Gay and lesbian studies--Washington (State)--Bellingham --History--Sources.; Environmentalism--Study and teaching--Washington (State) --Bellingham--History--Sources.; Recycling centers--Washington (State)--Lynden--History --Sources.; Theater--Study and teaching--Washington (State) --Bellingham--History--Sources.; Limnology--California--Mono Lake (Calif.)
Stehekin River (Wash.)--History--Sources.; Alaska--History--Sources.; Uruguay--Environmental conditions--Study and teaching --History--Sources.
Arts and Humanities; Sexuality; Fisheries and Wildlife; Performing Arts; Science; Environmental Conditions; Colleges and Universities
The following section contains a detailed listing of the materials in the collection.
- Personal and Family Papers, circa 1865-2004; Series I
  - Personal Papers, 1937-2004; Subseries 1
    - Transcripts, resumes, vitae, 1961-1980s (Box-folder 1/1)
    - Correspondence - Incoming
      - Loline Hathaway to David Mason, 1956-1967 (Box-folder 1/2)
      - M.S. to David Mason, 1957-1960 (Box-folder 1/3)
      - Jonathan Hough to David Mason, 1957-1968 (Box-folder 1/4)
      - Bernie Oordt to David Mason, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 1/5-1/6)
      - Chuck ___ to David Mason, 1973-1977 (Box-folder 1/7)
      - Thomas Belfield to David Mason, 1975 (Box-folder 1/8)
      - Various, 1955-2004 (Box-folder 1/9)
    - Correspondence - Outgoing
      - David Mason to Loline Hathaway, 1956-1961 (Box-folder 1/10)
      - David Mason to Jonathan Hough, 1957-1967 (Box-folder 1/11)
      - David Mason to Bernie Oordt, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 1/12)
      - David Mason to Lucile Mason and Herbert Mason, 1972-1974 (Box-folder 1/13)
      - Various, 1956-1977 (Box-folder 1/14)
      - Correspondence, notes and clippings concerning LSD use, 1966-1969 (Box-folder 1/15)
      - Chuckanut Village and other properties, 1970-1972; 1986 (Box-folder 1/16)
      - Berkeley High School Yearbook, 1954 (Box-folder 1/17)
      - UC Berkeley High School Reunion, 1979 (Box-folder 1/18)
    - Photographs
      - Baby album, 1937-1939 (Box-folder 1/19)
      - Loose baby photos, 1937-1939 (Box-folder 1/20)
      - Childhood, circa 1939-1950 (Box-folder 1/21)
      - Childhood, undated (Oversizefolder 1)
      - College, 1954-1956; circa 1958-1966 (Box-folder 1/22-1/23)
      - Adult, circa 1963-1991 (Box-folder 1/24)
      - Friends, circa 1960s-1990s (Box-folder 1/25)
      - Seattle Gay Pride Parade, circa 1980 (Box-folder 1/26)
      - Nature photographs, undated (Box-folder 1/27)
      - Trip to Japan, undated (Box-folder 1/28)
  - Family Papers, circa 1865-1990s; Subseries 2
    - Correspondence, 1939-1955 (Box-folder 1A/1)
    - Clippings Herbert and Lucile Mason, 1931-1932; 1946; 1972; 1989 (Box-folder 1A/2)
    - Notebooks, circa 1940; 1970; 1971; 1974; 1975 (Box-folder 1A/3)
    - Family datebooks, undated (Box-folder 1A/4)
    - Childhood music notebook, 1944 (Box-folder 1A/5)
    - Photographs
      - Herbert and Lucile Mason, 1931-1969 (Box-folder 1A/6)
      - Family and friends, circa 1919-1960s (Box-folder 1A/7)
      - "In Memoriam: Herbert Mason", 1994 (Box-folder 1A/8)
      - Adult, circa 1920s-1990s (Box-folder 2/1)
      - Family and friends, circa 1920s-1963 (Box-folder 2/2)
      - World War I, circa 1917 (Box-folder 2/3)
      - Alaska and Inuit, circa 1931 (Box-folder 2/4)
      - California, Washington, and Oregon, 1918-1946 (Box-folder 2/5)
      - Miscellaneous, circa 1920-1964 (Box-folder 2/6-2/7)
      - Lucile (Roush) Mason
        - Childhood, 1896-1914 (Box-folder 2/8)
        - School years, circa 1912-1933 (Box-folder 2/9-2/10)
        - Adult, 1942-1973 (Box-folder 2/11)
        - Amelia (Gunther) Roush (mother), circa 1912-1920s (Box-folder 2/12)
        - Thomas Roush (father), circa 1865-1934 (Box-folder 2/13)
        - Family and friends, circa 1912-1964 (Box-folder 2/14)
      - Travel
        - Yosemite National Park, 1916-1939 (Box-folder 2/15)
        - Stanford and Berkeley, California, circa 1916-1932 (Box-folder 2/16)
- Education and Career, circa 1954-2002; Series II
  - Course Materials, circa 1960-1999; Subseries 1
    - Biology 402 class notes and lectures, 1966-1993 (Box-folder 2/22)
    - Biology 402 class notes and lectures, 1966-1993 (Box-folder 2/17)
    - Biology 325 Connelly Creek project, stream studies, and "South Spur of Sehome Hill", circa 1989 (Box-folder 2/18)
    - Communication One and one reel (Super 8 film), circa 1970s (Box-folder 2/19)
    - Gay Studies Class
      - Articles and handouts, 1964-1999 (Box-folder 2/20-2/21)
      - Gay Academic Union pamphlets, brochures, "chapter starter kit," conference notes, 1974; 1978; 1979 (Box-folder 2/22)
      - National Gay Task Force materials, 1977 (Box-folder 2/23)
      - Gay Academic Union Journal, Gai Saber 1, no.1-4, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 2/24)
      - Clippings files related to gay rights, 1975-1993 (Box-folder 2/25)
      - Hypothesis re: AIDS and related publications, circa 1982 (Box-folder 2/26)
      - Sex roles class lecture, 1984 February 27 (Box-folder 2/27)
    - Lynden Recycling Class
      - 35mm slides, 1972 (Box 3)
      - Project notes and questionnaire, 1972 (Box-folder 4/1)
      - 16mm film reel, 1972 (Box-folder 4/2)
    - Opera class, 1995 (Box-folder 4/3)
  - Fairhaven College, 1974-1998; Subseries 2
    - Red Square Magazine article (includes a cover photograph of David Mason), 1987 (Box-folder 4/4)
    - Awards received and given, 1987-1992 (Box-folder 4/5)
    - Fairhaven College commencement programs with David T. Mason as master of ceremonies (includes slides), 1974; 1982; 1988; 1989; 1992; 1993 (Box-folder 4/6)
    - Retirement celebration invitation and photographs, 1998 (Box-folder 4/7)
    - Student photographs, undated (Box-folder 4/8)
  - Correspondence, 1960-1995; Subseries 3
    Correspondence is generally about the creation of the College of Environmental Studies including information about the interdisciplinary studies between Biology/Fairhaven and Huxley.
    - Academic Correspondence
      - Research on Anti-Discrimination policies of several universities and corporations, 1975-1984 (Box-folder 4/9)
      - TIAA-CREF participation, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 4/10)
      - Creation of the College of Environmental Studies, 1967-1968; 1986 (Box-folder 4/11)
      - Visiting Anthropology and Literary Scholar Sophia Morgan, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 4/12)
      - Letters of appreciation for teaching, 1967-1990 (Box-folder 4/13)
      - Rehire, Tenure, and Promotion (RTP) Committee, 1965-1995 (Box-folder 4/14)
      - Research Advisory Committee (RAC), 1985-1991 (Box-folder 4/15)
      - Hiring process and early career at Western Washington State College (WWSC), 1965-1970 (Box-folder 4/16)
    - Research
      - Experiments with platinum and silver electrodes concerning oxygen concentration in water, 1960-1961 (Box-folder 4/17)
      - Sabbatical to South America and the southwestern Pacific (includes photos), 1980-1981 (Box-folder 4/18)
      - Correspondence to Fairhaven College from Africa, 1972-1974 (Box-folder 4/19)
      - Project co-ordinations with David Scholl, 1964-1968 (Box-folder 4/20)
      - Critiques of other academic studies, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 4/21)
  - Speaking Engagements, 1966-1998; Subseries 4
    - General correspondence related to speaking engagements, 1967-1995 (Box-folder 4/22)
    - Letters of appreciation, 1969-1995 (Box-folder 4/23-4/25)
    - Speeches and papers given at professional meetings and classes, circa 1966-1990 (Box-folder 4/26)
    - Publicity and clippings relating to seminars and performances, 1969-1998 (Box-folder 4/27-4/28)
  - Publications, 1966-1991; Subseries 5
    - Correspondence relating to papers submitted for publication, 1966-1981 (Box-folder 4/29)
    - "FAST" [Faculty/Staff publication of WWU], 1985-1991 (Box-folder 4/30)
    - "Lace Wing: A Fragment," Ecosphere 2 (January 1971): 9-10, 1971 January (Box-folder 4/31)
    - Abstracts of papers presented at the American Society of Limnology and Oceanography meeting, 1980 (Box-folder 4/32)
    - "Exorcizing the Engineer."California Engineer (March 1970): 32-33, 1970 March (Box-folder 4/33)
    - "Post-Deep Ecology, or Yes, Good is Bad" presentation, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 4/34)
    - Reports
      - "Bioassays of Lower Trophic Levels, Volume VI of a Study of Toxicity and Biostimulation in San Francisco Bay_Delta Waters," Berkeley, 1971 (Box-folder 4/35)
      - "Water Resources Engineering Education Series, Program VIII: Freshwater Lakes and Their Management", 1971 (Box-folder 4/36)
      - "An Approach to Quantitative Morality for Engineers: The Strongest Counter Oar.", undated (Box-folder 4/37)
  - Major Research Projects, 1960s-1999; Subseries 6
    - Mono Lake, California
      - Correspondence, affadavits, and research related to Sierra Club lawsuit, 1979; 1997 (Box-folder 5/1-5/2)
      - Publications
        - "Biologically Precipitated Tufa at Mono Lake", 1964-1965 (Box-folder 5/3)
        - Data and notes relating to publication, 1960s-1970s (Box-folder 5/4)
        - Thesis: "Limnology of Mono Lake California", 1967 (Box-folder 5/5)
      - Film: "Lichen and Grout", circa 1977 (Box-folder 5/6)
    - Alaska
      - Correspondence relating to research, 1978-1987 (Box-folder 5/7)
      - Climate data, 1977-1981 (Box-folder 5/8)
      - Reports and Publications
        - Atlantic Richfield Company (ARCO), Instituto Nacional de Investigaciones Agropecurias (INIAP-NAPO), Alaskan Arctic, 1977; 1979; 1980; 1983; 1989 (Box-folder 5/9)
        - "A Bioassay on a Shore Fly at Prudhoe Bay" and "A Study of Petroleum Toxicity to a Shore Fly at Prudhoe Bay", 1978 (Box-folder 5/10)
        - "Arctic Salt Marsh Lakes", 1981 (Box-folder 5/11)
        - "Biological Stress-strain Relationships in Arctic Salt Marsh Ecosystems", 1981 (Box-folder 5/12)
        - "Environmental Assessment of Selected Habitats in Arctic Littoral Systems.", 1979 April 1-1980 March 31 (Box-folder 5/13)
        - "Effect of Vegetation, Crude Oil, and a Vehicle Track on Salt Marsh," and "Soil Strength in Arctic Alaska, U.S.A.", 1980s (Box-folder 5/14)
        - "Reconnaissance Characterization of Littoral Biota, Beaufort and Chickchi Seas.", 1977 April 1-1978 March 31 (Box-folder 5/15)
        - Habitats in Arctic Littoral Systems (report), 1977-1979 (Box-folder 5/16)
        - Environmental Assessment of Selected Habitats in Arctic Littoral Systems, WWU Report, 1980 (Box-folder 5/17)
    - Prudhoe Bay
      - Presentation Materials
        - Transparencies, Prudhoe Bay, 1970s (Box-folder 5/18)
        - Transparencies, "positives" of Prudhoe Bay, 1970s (Box-folder 5/19)
      - Photographs
        - Prudhoe Bay, 1970s (Box-folder 5/20)
        - Aquatic macrophytes (PVO), 1989 (Box-folder 5/21)
      - Research Notes
        - Data and notes, 1977-1989 (Box-folder 5/22-5A/5)
        - Outer Continental Shelf Environmental Assessment Program (OCSEAP), 1970-1986 (Box-folder 5A/6)
    - Uruguay - Fulbright Scholarship
      - Correspondence and research notes, 1972 (Box-folder 5A/7)
      - Notebook and travel receipts, 1972 (Box-folder 5A/8)
      - Photos of the Ektar 125 salt marsh, 1999 May 5 (Box-folder 5A/9)
    - Stehekin River
      - Publications
        - "Habitat Values of Woody Debris Accumulations of the Lower Stehekin River, with Notes on Disturbances of Alluvial Gravels.", 1985 (Box-folder 6/1)
        - "Follow-up Study of Habitat Values of the Lower Stehekin River," and "Appendix V: Small Animal Mycophagy" by Fred Rhodes, 1985 (Box-folder 6/2)
        - "Ecosystem Impact of Disturbance of Alluvial Gravel and Woody Debris along the Lower Stehekin River Channel.", 1985 (Box-folder 6/3)
        - "Small Mammal Microhabitats Influenced by Riparian Woody Debris," and "Running Head: Small Mammals Influenced by Woody Debris.", 1986 (Box-folder 6/4)
        - Prose: "Stehekin Debris: Narrative of a Wood Pile," presentation and transparencies, 1985 (Box-folder 6/5)
      - Research Notes and Data
        - Notes and Data, 1981-1985 (Box-folder 6/6-6/7)
        - Audio cassettes (data gathered at site), 1984 June-August (Box 6A)
        - National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration weather and climate data, 1987 (Box-folder 7/1)
  - Minor Research Projects, 1966-2002; Subseries 7
    - Washington
      - Lake Whatcom, water level graphs, 1966-1968 (Oversize-folder 2)
      - Correspondence regarding Georgia Pacific mercury discharge litigation, 1970-1994 (Box-folder 7/2)
      - Georgia Pacific chlorine/mercury deposits reference and notes, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 7/3)
      - Nooksack River, data and correspondence, 1993 (Box-folder 7/4)
      - VAX (computing system) instructions, and data sheets, circa 1982 (Box-folder 7/5)
    - Oregon
      - Lake Abert, project budget information, project notes and data, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 7/6)
      - Lake Abert, correspondence, 1994-1997 (Box-folder 7/7)
      - Research photos of Mount St. Helens, undated (Box-folder 7/8)
      - Minor research reports Lake Abert, undated (Box-folder 7/9)
      - ODFW Scientific Taking permits, undated (Box-folder 7/10)
      - Lakeview Resource Area Planning update, 2002 (Box-folder 7/11)
    - South America
      - Columbia, leaf research, data and slides, 1979-1981 (Box-folder 7/12)
  - Film, circa 1978; Subseries 8
    - Flamingos and beetles in Nyika Africa (super 8), undated; FILE REMOVED (Box-folder 7/13)
    - Geese, foam (super 8), circa 1978; FILE REMOVED (Box-folder 7/14)
  - Slides, 1954-1989; Subseries 9
    - Alaska, Ski Ski Beach, 1977-1979; 1982 (Box 7A)
    - Alaska, Tahiti, Colorado, Washington (Whatcom County, Bellingham, Mount Baker), 1961-1978 (Box 7B)
    - Arctic, North Sweden, Alaska, New Zealand, South America, Hawaii/Fiji, 1954-1974 (Box 7C)
    - South America, Australasia, Ghana, Cape Town, Hawaii, New Zealand, Australia, 1972; 1980 (Box 7D)
    - Australia, South America (Ecuador), Asia (Phillippines, Japan), 1980; 1989 (Box 7E)
    - California, Mexico, Whatcom County, Artistic and Abstract Works (Food, Words, Reflections, Self), circa 1983 (Box 7F)
    - Bellingham, 'South Side', 1972-1976 (Box 7G)
    - 'South Side', Mono 1976, Stehokin, circa 1976 (Box 7H)
  - Field Notebooks, 1975-1999; Subseries 10
    - Untitled yellow notebook, Mining Transit, 1976 (Box 7I)
    - South America, undated (Box 7I)
    - Todd Rollins: Biology 325, Ecology, 1988 (Box 7I)
    - Retirement, 1998 (Box 7I)
    - Untitled tan notebook, undated (Box 7I)
    - Plants, Fungi, Field notebook, undated (Box 7I)
    - Untitled, Mining Transit notebook, 1975 (Box 7I)
    - Padden Lagoon/Red River, 1991-1992 (Box 7I)
    - Important Field Data, Flat Rock, Field Book, 1994-1995 (Box 7I)
    - Vital Field Notebook, 1977 (Box 7I)
    - Untitled, Handi Notes, undated (Box 7I)
    - Course of the Steam, Field Notebook, 1987 July (Box 7I)
    - Nesset Farm, Transit Notebook, 1999 (Box 7I)
    - Photocopy of untitled notebook, 1983 (Box 7I)
    - Untitled, Mining Transit Notebook, 1975 (Box 7I)
    - Sehome, Field Notebook, 1991 (Box 7I)
    - Plants, Mining Transit Notebook, 1976 (Box 7I)
    - Plants Collection, Mining Transit Notebook, 1975 (Box 7I)
    - Urban Wildlife, Transit notebook, 1989 (Box 7I)
    - Field Notes and data: mammals, weather, vegetation (2 discs), 1994; 1995 (Box 7I)
    - Black with red edging, 1982-1983 (Box 7J)
    - Yellow with white tape from bottom left to top right, includes letter, 1983-1984 (Box 7J)
    - 1979 Alaska – Includes copy of passport, photographs of David Mason, and negatives. (Box 7J)
    - Yellow 1981-AK – field notes, 1961; 1981-1982 (Box 7J)
    - Orange EEN-1977 – field notes (Box 7J)
    - Orange AK 1976 – field notes (Box 7J)
    - Yellow ABERT-I + plants, 1994-1995 (Box 7J)
    - Yellow Mono – Mono Mouse Habitat, contains plant stem with leaves., 1997 (Box 7J)
    - 1978-KOTZ-II-78 – field notes, 1977-1978 (Box 7J)
    - PUO-1978 II – field notes, 1978-1982 (Box 7J)
    - Orange – field notebook, 1980-1982 (Box 7J)
    - Yellow AK89 – field notes, 1989 (Box 7J)
- Theatre, 1970-1998; Series III
  - Production Materials, 1970-1998; Subseries 1
    - Background information, resumes, theater vitae, circa 1980s (Box-folder 8/1)
    - Cast lists, undated (Box-folder 8/2)
    - Correspondence relating to productions, 1973-1998 (Box-folder 8/3)
    - Publicity posters, 1970s-1990s (Box-folder 8/4)
    - Programs of events, 1970s-1990s (Box-folder 8/5)
    - Budget information, 1977; circa 1980; 1991 (Box-folder 8/6)
    - Clippings, reviews, 1977-1990s (Box-folder 8/7)
    - Notes and background information on Bertolt Brecht's productions, 1980s (Box-folder 8/8)
    - "Three Penny Opera" character sketches, 1980s (Box-folder 8/9)
    - "Darling of the Day" sound recording, review, "The Crucible" mini-script, and ephemera, undated (Box-folder 8/10)
    - "Edward II" songs (music tape), undated (Box-folder 8/11)
    - "Mother Courage" - Brecht (music tape), undated (Box-folder 8/10)
  - Scripts, 1986-1998; Subseries 2